# MUHAMMAD KAFEEL FAROOQI

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 19 September 1993

Permanent Address: Vill & P/O. Utla Gadoon, Teh. Topi, Dist. Swabi

Present Address: Same as permanent address
Country: Pakistan

Province: Khyber Pakhtunkhwa
City of Birth: Swabi
Mobile: +923161969790

Email: <u>kafeelfarooqi67@gmail.com</u>
Social Website: <u>http://www.facebook.com/kafeel1993</u>



#### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

I am an enthusiastic, confident, outgoing qualified Mechanical Engineer having problem solving, AutoCAD and computer skills along with the ability to do work under pressure. Having versatile nature my communication and interpersonal skills are spiffing and therefor I love to communicate with people at all levels in a friendly and professional manner. I enjoy working in a team environment. Theoretical concepts of the course of Mechanical Engineering and experiences makes me productive for any organization.

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Currently looking for a career starting opportunity as a Mechanical Engineer in an organization where I can imply my knowledge and skills practically to achieve organizational goals individually as well as part of team.

## **EDUCATION**

March 2013 - December 2017

### BE Mechanical,

Balochistan University of Engineering and Technology, Khuzdar.

- Gold Medalist
- CGPA of 3.97/4
- Percentage of 93
- Group leader of Final Year Project
- Title of Final Year Project "Construction of Hover-Bike Model Powered By Battery".

## September 2010 – July 2012

## Intermediate (Pre-Engineering),

Govt. Higher Secondary School Chanai Gadoon, Swabi.

BISE Mardan

- Achieved 1<sup>st</sup> position in class
- Marks obtained 845/1100
- Percentage 76
- Selected for the "Stoori da KPK" merit scholarship.

# April 2008 - June 2010

## Matriculation (Science),

Govt. High School Utla Gadoon, Swabi.

BISE Mardan

- Achieved 1<sup>st</sup> position in class
- Marks Obtained 851/1050
- Percentage 81.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

1. July 2017 – September 2017

Internee

Fouji Fertilizers Company Pvt Ltd

Goth Maachi, Sadiqabad.

"First week of Internship was based on the training and safety precautions of working in a Fertilizer Plant. After training the preceding internship period was consumed on the maintenance of Mechanical Seals, Centrifugal Pumps, Positive Displacement Compressors and Heat Exchangers.

2. December 2015 - January 2016

Internee

Pakistan State Oil

Teen talwar, Clifton, Karachi.

"During internship I was able to accomplish various tasks individually as well as in team while leading the team like Risks assessment, modeling the conditioned air network on AutoCAD and also participated in Lube Gala.

## **MEMBERSHIPS**

I am proud member of:

- ASME
- Helping Hands Foundation BUETK Chapter
- Students Action Committee BUETK Chapter
- Literary Society BUET Khuzdar.

# **SKILLS**

AutoCAD Intermediate
 C++ Intermediate
 MS Word Excellent
 MS Excel Intermediate
 MS PowerPoint Excellent

# **LANGUAGES**

English
 Urdu
 Pashto
 Excellent
 Native

## **INTERESTS**

- Poetry
- Books Reading

**Problem Solving** 

- Chess
- Cards
- Cricket

## **REFERENCE**

Registrar BUET Khuzdar. Email: registrar@buetk.edu.pk Phone: +92848550274

Excellent